We are going to learn how to assign Microsoft 365 license to a single user or
multiple users at the same time and doing that manually. So let's say you
work as an IT system administrator and you've been asked to assign a user
license. So what you can't really do is the following. You will need to
totally go to your Microsoft 365 of dot com or office dot com and then go to
your admin center and in admin center, yeah, you need to totally set for the
user. For example, you can see we have some users without license. So I can
select the first user and select the second user and then click manage product
license and then we can assign keep the existing license and assign more here
we can select its specific license. But for example, I can decide to also assign
its specific user a license, can just click manage product license and here
you can see we can decide to assign this user a license. Let me just assign
this user a license. We see how three of 10 license available they will
cannot leave to see if changes. But you can also assign license to a security
group. For example, you can go to your groups. If I go to teams and groups, here
you can see we have the active teams and groups, then you can really create a
security groups. You can create a security group and in the security group, you
go to actually assign license to that security group. So which means that every
single user that's included in that group, we have the license to Microsoft
365. We'll mind you every single when you assign license, go to consume a
single when you assign it license to the security group and you are adding more
user for example 10 users to that group. I only have 10 available license. It's
going to consume that 10 license. I will also use the Azure Active Directory to
also assign license to use our even Microsoft Intio. We will see that in
different video. So this is how you assign license to a user using the Microsoft
365 admin center.